
// general knowledge
const quiz1 = [
    {
        number: "1",
        question: "In early January, which country landed the first human-made object on the far side of the Moon?",
        answer: "china",
        hint: "Beijing is the capitol city"

    },
    {
        number: "2",
        question: "The NHS banned the purchasing of which piece of equipment - the first experimental version being invented by Scotland's Alexander Bain in 1846?",
        answer: "fax machines",
        hint: "A piece of office equipment which is rarely used nowadays"
    },
    {
        number: "3",
        question: 'Who was unhurt, "but very, very shocked and shaken."?',
        answer: "the duke of edinburgh",
        hint: "This person is a royal"
    },
    {
        number: "4",
        question: "Premier League striker Emiliano Sala's plane went missing while on a flight from Nantes to which British city?",
        answer: "cardiff",
        hint: "A Welsh city"
    },
    {
        number: "5",
        question: "Who announced he was leaving The National Television Awards after 9 years as host?",
        answer: "dermot o'leary",
        hint: "Also a BBC radio 2 presenter"
    },
    {
        number: "6",
        question: "A picture of which everyday object on Instagram became a global phenomenon by becoming the most liked post in online history?",
        answer: "an egg (known as the instagram egg)",
        hint: "Which came first the chicken or the ...?"
    },
    {
        number: "7",
        question: "Who launched a legal action against the makers of Channel 4's The Jump after fracturing vertebrae in 2016?",
        answer: "beth tweddle",
        hint: "A British gymnast"
    },
    {
        number: "8",
        question: "January saw the sad death of actor Windsor Davies; in which 'Carry On' film did he play Sergeant-Major 'Tiger' Bloomer?",
        answer: "carry on england",
        hint: "Initial release October 1976"
    },
    {
        number: "9",
        question: "Which city's MP became the first sitting MP to be jailed in 28 years?",
        answer: "peterborough's",
        hint: "The city is in Northamptonshire"
    },
    {
        number: "10",
        question: "The U.S. Justice Department charged which Chinese tech firm with multiple counts of fraud?",//question 10
        answer: "huawei",
        hint: "Sounds like a island state located in the Pacific ocean"
    },
    {
        number: "11",
        question: "On February the 3rd, who arrived in Abu Dhabi in the United Arab Emirates?",
        answer: "pope francis (becoming the first pope to visit the arabian peninsula)",
        hint: "Wears a white pointy hat"
    },
    {
        number: "12",
        question: "Which European country renamed itself, hence ending a decades-old dispute with Greece?",
        answer: "the republic of macedonia renamed itself the republic of north macedonia",
        hint: "This country is landlocked between Albania, Bulgaria, Kosovo, Serbia and greece "
    },
    {
        number: "13",
        question: "The court-case featuring Joaquin Archivaldo Guzman Loera made world headlines, by what name is this Mexican drug lord better known?",
        answer: "el chapo",
        hint: "Its not Pablo Escobar"
    },
    {
        number: "14",
        question: "Albert Finney sadly passed away. In the classic 1960 film Saturday Night and Sunday Morning which product did his character Arthur Seaton make in a Nottingham factory?",
        answer: "raleigh bicycles",
        hint: "This company is one of the oldest manufactures of ... in the world"
    },
    {
        number: "15",
        question: "Change UK – The Independent Group was founded, who was its interim leader?",
        answer: "heidi allen",
        hint: "Current political party is the Liberal Democrats"
    },
    {
        number: "16",
        question: "Who became the oldest football manager in Premier League history, at the age of 71 years and 198 days?",
        answer: "roy hodgson (crystal palace)",
        hint: "A former England manager"
    },
    {
        number: "17",
        question: "Who did BBC Two viewers vote the most iconic figure of the 20th Century following a series that asked the public to name the century's greatest figure?",
        answer: "alan turing",
        hint: "Best known for mathematics and computer science"
    },
    {
        number: "18",
        question: "Who announces his intention to step down from his presenting role on BBC Radio 4's The Today Programme later in the year?",
        answer: "john humphrys",
        hint: "BBC news Nine O'clock presenter"
    },
    {
        number: "19",
        question: "The family of which American fiction writer confirm that he left a large unpublished body of work on his death in 2010 which they are preparing for publication?",
        answer: "j. d. salinger",
        hint: "Famous works include The Catcher in the Rye, Franny and Zooey and Nine Stories"
    },
    {
        number: "20",
        question: "Chelsea goalkeeper Kepa Arrizabalaga apologised for refusing to do what during the Cup final?",
        answer: "leaving the pitch/ refused to be substituted",
        hint: "This players nationality is Spanish"
    } 
];

// end of quiz 1

// history
const quiz2 = [
    {
        number: "1",
        question: "As recently dramatised in a critically acclaimed miniseries, what year did the Chernobyl disaster occur?",
        answer: "1986",
        hint: "The space shuttle challenger is destroyed this year"
    },
    {
        number: "2",
        question: "Who was Lord Mayor of London four times between 1397 and 1419, and the inspiration for a classic English folk tale?",
        answer: "richard (dick) whittington",
        hint: "Famous for travelling with his cat"
    },
    {
        number: "3",
        question: "Who was the second President of the United States?",
        answer: "john adams",
        hint: "This president was a leader of the American Revolution"
    },
    {
        number: "4",
        question: "Who was the only one of Henry VIII’s wives to receive a Queen’s funeral?",
        answer: "jane seymour",
        hint: "The third wife of Henry VIII"
    },
    {
        number: "5",
        question: "Which British archaeologist discovered Tutankhamun’s tomb?",
        answer: "howard carter",
        hint: "When Carnarvon asked “Can you see anything?”, Carter replied with the famous words: “Yes, wonderful things!”"
    },
    {
        number: "6",
        question: "Who was the leader of Britain’s ill-fated Antarctic expedition which was one of the first to reach the South Pole in 1912?",
        answer: "robert f. scott",
        hint: "Died on the Ross ice Shelf, Antartica"
    },
    {
        number: "7",
        question: "In which European country was there a civil war between 1946 and 1949?",
        answer: "greece",
        hint: "The capitol is Athens"
    },
    {
        number: "8",
        question: "Which 13th Century Scottish knight did Mel Gibson portray in Braveheart?",
        answer: "william wallace",
        hint: "Quoted to have said: Every man dies, not every man truly lives."
    },
    {
        number: "9",
        question: "Which war was fought in South Africa between 1899 and 1902?",
        answer: "second boer war",
        hint: "Between the British Empire and two idependent states"
    },
    {
        number: "10",
        question: "In which country did the Second World War Battles of El Alamein take place?",
        answer: "egypt",
        hint: "The capitol is Cairo"
    },
    {
        number: "11",
        question: "Who discovered the wreckage of the Titanic?",
        answer: "robert ballard",
        hint: "Passed away ages 78"
    },
    {
        number: "12",
        question: "What year did the Challenger Space Shuttle disaster take place?",
        answer: "1986",
        hint: "This year the Chernobyl Nuclear Disaster happened"
    },
    {
        number: "13",
        question: "What year was the Magna Carta signed?",
        answer: "1215",
        hint: "This is a royal charter of rights agreed by King John of England"
    },
    {
        number: "14",
        question: "Which British King suffered from a stammer, as portrayed by Colin Firth in The King’s Speech?",
        answer: "king george vi",
        hint: "A 2010 film called the kings speech depicted this King's struggle with speech"
    },
    {
        number: "15",
        question: "What was the name of the ship that brought news of the Battle of Trafalgar to Britain?",
        answer: "hms pickle",
        hint: "Originally a civilian vessel, then purchased and used by the royal navy"
    },
    {
        number: "16",
        question: "Which pilot famously fought in the Battle of Britain with two artificial legs?",
        answer: "douglas bader",
        hint: "He was credited for 22 aerial victories"
    },
    {
        number: "17",
        question: "When did the Korean War end?",
        answer: "it didn’t – an armistice was signed in 1953 but the two countries are still technically at war",
        hint: "The famous 38th parrellel is home to a stand off even today"
    },
    {
        number: "18",
        question: "Which famous American expolorer was born in Scranton, Pennsylvania?",
        answer: "hugh glass",
        hint: "Depicted in the 2015 movie the Revenant"
    },
    {
        number: "19",
        question: "Which vessel is famous for having the bloodiest mutiny in the Royal Navy's history?",
        answer: "hms hermione",
        hint: "This name was later to be given to a Leander-class frigate"
    },
    {
        number: "20",
        question: "Who discovered penicillin?",
        answer: "alexander fleming",
        hint: "This man was Scottish physician and microbiologist"
    }

]

// geography
const quiz3 = [
    {
        number: "1",
        question: "Which river flows through Paris?",
        answer: "river seine",
        hint: "Eventually flows to the English channel"
    },
    {
        number: "2",
        question: "In which country is the UK’s highest mountain, Ben Nevis?",
        answer: "scotland",
        hint: "This country covers the northern third of the island of Great Britan"
    },
    {
        number: "3",
        question: "Mount Vesuvius overlooks which modern Italian city?",
        answer: "naples",
        hint: "Also home to the Duomo di San Gennaro cathedral"
    },
    {
        number: "4",
        question: "What is the highest active volcano in Europe?",
        answer: "mount etna",
        hint: "Located on Sicily"
    },
    {
        number: "5",
        question: "Which European capital city is divided by canals into about 90 islands joined by about 400 bridges?",
        answer: "amsterdam",
        hint: "Cycling is a key part of this city"
    },
    {
        number: "6",
        question: "What’s the world’s biggest port?",
        answer: "port of shanghai",
        hint: "Over took Port of singapore to become the worlds bussiest"
    },
    {
        number: "7",
        question: "Which South American country has land borders with ten other countries?",
        answer: "brazil",
        hint: "The largest South American country"
    },
    {
        number: "8",
        question: "Which city is also known as ‘The Eternal City’?",
        answer: "rome",
        hint: "The capitol city of Italy"
    },
    {
        number: "9",
        question: "The Great Barrier Reef is off the coast of which Australian state?",
        answer: "queensland",
        hint: "The capitol is Brisbane"
    },
    {
        number: "10",
        question: "Which island would you Visit to kiss the Blarney Stone?",
        answer: "ireland",
        hint: "Formerly part of the United Kingdom"
    },
    {
        number: "11",
        question: "In which country would you be if you were Visiting the Taj Mahal?",
        answer: "india",
        hint: "The second most populus country in the world"
    },
    {
        number: "12",
        question: "In which Scandinavian country would you find fjords?",
        answer: "norway",
        hint: "Capitol city is Oslo"
    },
    {
        number: "13",
        question: "Which country’s name could be part of a Christmas dinner?",
        answer: "turkey",
        hint: "Capitol Ankara"
    },
    {
        number: "14",
        question: "Which stretch of water separates Anglesey and Wales?",
        answer: "menai strait",
        hint: "This strait is crossed in two places"
    },
    {
        number: "15",
        question: "In which continent is the world’s longest river, the Nile?",
        answer: "africa",
        hint: "The worlds second largest continent"
    },
    {
        number: "16",
        question: "What colour is the spot in the middle of the Japanese flag?",
        answer: "red",
        hint: "Symbolises the sun"
    },
    {
        number: "17",
        question: "Is Australia in the northern or the southern hemisphere?",
        answer: "southern",
        hint: "Water will flow counter clockwise here"
    },
    {
        number: "18",
        question: "What does each star on the flag of the United States stand for?",
        answer: "a state",
        hint: "There are 52 of these"
    },
    {
        number: "19",
        question: " Which bridge, one of the oldest roadway bridges in the United States, was completed in 1883 and spans the East River?",
        answer: "brooklyn bridge",
        hint: "Located in New York"
    },
    {
        number: "20",
        question: "On an O.S Map with a scale of 1:25000, how many inches represent one mile?",
        answer: "Two and a half",
        hint: "Similar to a famous american sitcom"
    }

]

// Sport
const quiz4 = [
    {
        number: "1",
        question: "What is Usain Bolt’s 100m world record time?",
        answer: "9.58 seconds",
        hint: "Sub - 10 seconds"
    },
    {
        number: "2",
        question: "Which England footballer was famously never given a yellow card?",
        answer: "gary lineker",
        hint: "Appears in adverts for walkers crisps"
    },
    {
        number: "3",
        question: "How many world titles has Phil Talyor won in darts?",
        answer: "16",
        hint: "Between 14 and 18"
    },
    {
        number: "4",
        question: "Who is the only player to have scored in the Premier League, Championship, League 1, League 2, Conference, FA Cup, League Cup, Football League Trophy, FA Trophy, Champions League, Europa League, Scottish Premier League, Scottish Cup and Scottish League Cup?",
        answer: "gary hooper",
        hint: "Born 1988, Harlow"
    },
    {
        number: "5",
        question: "The LA Lakers and New York Knicks play which sport?",
        answer: "basketball",
        hint: "Typically played professionally on an indoor court"
    },
    {
        number: "6",
        question: "Katarina Johnson-Thompson is world champion in which sport?",
        answer: "heptathlon",
        hint: "This sport is combination of track and field, consisting of seven events"
    },
    {
        number: "7",
        question: "Which country did F1 legend Ayrton Senna come from?",
        answer: "brazil",
        hint: "The largest South American country"
    },
    {
        number: "8",
        question: "A penalty in football is taken how many yards away from the goal?",
        answer: "12 yards",
        hint: "Between 10 and 14 yards"
    },
    {
        number: "9",
        question: "Who holds the women's record for the 100m sprint?",
        answer: "florence griffith-joyner",
        hint: "Known as Flo-Jo"
    },
    {
        number: "10",
        question: "What club were West Ham United founded as?",
        answer: "thames ironworks",
        hint: "The Hammers symbolise these club"
    },
    {
        number: "11",
        question: "Who has scored the most Premier League hat-tricks?",
        answer: "sergio aguero",
        hint: "Argentine footballer"
    },
    {
        number: "12",
        question: "Who were Man Utd playing when Eric Cantona leaped into the crowd and kicked a fan?",
        answer: "crystal palace",
        hint: "Located in Selhurst, South London"
    },
    {
        number: "13",
        question: "In which sport do you wear a plastron?",
        answer: "fencing",
        hint: "Points are awarded in this sport by the sabre hitting the opponent"
    },
    {
        number: "14",
        question: "Which sport involves tucks and pikes?",
        answer: "diving",
        hint: "Tom Daley has two gold medals in this sport"
    },
    {
        number: "15",
        question: "Who is the Premier League’s all-time top scorer?",
        answer: "alan shearer",
        hint: "Currently a match of the day presenter"
    },
    {
        number: "16",
        question: "Jessica Ennis-Hill competed for Great Britain in which sport?",
        answer: "heptathlon",
        hint: "This sport is combination of track and field, consisting of seven events"
    },
    {
        number: "17",
        question: "England won the 2003 Rugby World Cup thanks to an iconic, last-gasp drop goal from Jonny Wilkinson. How many points did England score in that famous match?",
        answer: "20",
        hint: "Between 17 and 21"
    },
    {
        number: "18",
        question: "Which famous football manager once said: “I wouldn’t say I was the best manager in the business. But I was in the top one”?",
        answer: "bryan clough",
        hint: "Quoted to have said: They say Rome wasn't built in a day, but I wasn't on that particular job."
    },
    {
        number: "19",
        question: "How many F1 championships has Lewis Hamilton won?",
        answer: "6",
        hint: "Between 3 and 8"
    },
    {
        number: "20",
        question: " Chris Wilder helped guide Sheffield United from League One to the Premier League. In the Blades' League One title-winning season, how many points did they accumulate?",
        answer: "100",
        hint: "Between 94 and 112"
    }

]

// politics
const quiz5 = [
    {
        number: "1",
        question: "Which state was George W Bush governor of before becoming President of the United States?",
        answer: "texas",
        hint: "The second largest US state"
    },
    {
        number: "2",
        question: "Which former British Prime Minister graduated from Oxford University in 1947 with Second-Class Honours in Chemistry?",
        answer: "margaret thatcher",
        hint: "Known as the iron-lady"
    },
    {
        number: "3",
        question: "How long does Prime Minister’s Questions last?",
        answer: "thirty minutes",
        hint: "Less that three quarters of an hour but more than fifteen minutes"
    },
    {
        number: "4",
        question: "A member of which band threw a bucket of water over John Prescott at the 1998 Brit Awards?",
        answer: "chumbawamba",
        hint: "The lead singer was Dunstan Bruce"
    },
    {
        number: "5",
        question: "What did Theresa May claim was the naughtiest thing she had done as a child in a 2017 interview?",
        answer: "ran through fields of wheat",
        hint: "Farmers would not be best pleased"
    },
    {
        number: "6",
        question: "Which politician described Russia as “a riddle, wrapped in a mystery, inside an enigma”?",
        answer: "winston Churchill",
        hint: "Statue stands directly outside The Palace of Westminster"
    },
    {
        number: "7",
        question: "What is the name of the gallery for members of the public to watch The House of Commons?",
        answer: "strangers’ gallery",
        hint: "Located above the Commons"
    },
    {
        number: "8",
        question: "What is the official name of Big Ben?",
        answer: "elizabeth tower",
        hint: "It was renamed for the Queens diamond jubliee"
    },
    {
        number: "9",
        question: "What animal is the symbol of the US Democratic Party?",
        answer: "donkey",
        hint: "A common farm yard animal"
    },
    {
        number: "10",
        question: "Who is the current King of Jordan?",
        answer: "abdullah II",
        hint: "In 1980 he graduated from the Royal Military Academy in Sandhurst"
    },
    {
        number: "11",
        question: "Where did Richard Nixon hold his famous “I’m Not a Crook” press conference?",
        answer: "disney world",
        hint: "Perhaps Mickey mouse was watching?"
    },
    {
        number: "12",
        question: "Who was the only British Prime Minister to be assassinated?",
        answer: "spencer perceval",
        hint: "Born November 1762"
    },
    {
        number: "13",
        question: "Which US President was diagnosed with polio after becoming paralysed from the waist down?",
        answer: "franklin d. roosevelt",
        hint: "Often referred to as FDR"
    },
    {
        number: "14",
        question: "What were French Fries renamed to in several US Congressional cafeterias after France refused to support the Iraq War?",
        answer: "freedom fries",
        hint: "*Similar to liberty* - fries"
    },
    {
        number: "15",
        question: "Former leader of Change UK Anna Soubry used to be a presenter on which long-running daytime show?",
        answer: "this morning",
        hint: "Currently being presented by Holly Willoughby"
    },
    {
        number: "16",
        question: "True or false: in 2002 the President of Turkmenistan renamed the month of January after himself",
        answer: "true",
        hint: "January would now be called 'Turkmenbashi'"
    },
    {
        number: "17",
        question: "During the State Opening of Parliament, the doors of the House of Lords are shut in front of Black Rod – what historical event does this ritual date back to?",
        answer: "english civil war",
        hint: "From 22 August 1642 - 3 September 1651"
    },
    {
        number: "18",
        question: "“If you let a bully come into your front yard, the next day he’ll be on your porch” is a quote from which US President?",
        answer: "lyndon b. johnson",
        hint: "Ofton referred to as LBJ"
    },
    {
        number: "19",
        question: "How long is a French President elected for?",
        answer: "five years",
        hint: "Between three and 6 years"
    },
    {
        number: "20",
        question: "Which Conservative politician famously fed British beef to his daughter, in a press event to prove its safety from B.S.E?",
        answer: "john gummer",
        hint: "Brother of Peter Gummer, Baron Chadlington"
    }

]


// music
const quiz6 = [
    {
        number: "1",
        question: "Which English Sir has had No. l’s in the 50’s, 60’s, 70’s, 80’s and 90’s?",
        answer: "sir cliff richard",
        hint: "Singer of song Devil Woman"
    },
    {
        number: "2",
        question: "Billy Corgan is the lead singer of which alternative rock band?",
        answer: "the smashing pumpkins",
        hint: "2007 album Zeitgeist"
    },
    {
        number: "3",
        question: "Who had a No.1 hit with Ice Ice Baby?",
        answer: "vanilla ice",
        hint: "Full name: Robert Matthew Van Winkle"
    },
    {
        number: "4",
        question: "Jimmy, Robert, John and John: can you identify this rock band from the first names of their original line-up?",
        answer: "led zeppelin",
        hint: "Songs: Stairway to Heaven"
    },
    {
        number: "5",
        question: "What is the middle name of Sir Paul McCartney?",
        answer: "Paul",
        hint: "James is his first name"
    },
    {
        number: "6",
        question: "How many members are there in pop group Little Mix?",
        answer: "4",
        hint: "Between 2 and 7"
    },
    {
        number: "7",
        question: "Which famous film star danced (and flew) in the video to Fatboy Slim’s 2001 track Weapon of choice?",
        answer: "christopher walken",
        hint: "Quoted to have said: Obviously an actor draws on his own experience."
    },
    {
        number: "8",
        question: "Which 1977 hit single by the Spanish vocal duo Baccara is the best-selling single of all-time by a female group?",
        answer: "yes sir, i can boogie",
        hint: "Released in 1977"
    },
    {
        number: "9",
        question: "In what year did Elvis Presley die? (a bonus point for the month)",
        answer: "1977",
        hint: "This year Jimmy Carter became the 39th President of the United States"
    },
    {
        number: "10",
        question: "In 1975 Bohemian Rhapsody was number one for nine weeks. It was finally knocked off the top slot by a song with a name that appears in the lyrics of Bohemian Rhapsody. Name the song and the band that ended Queen’s number one success.",
        answer: "mamma mia by abba",
        hint: "Released 1975"
    },
    {
        number: "11",
        question: "What was Britney Spears’ first single called?",
        answer: "baby one more time",
        hint: "Released 1998"
    },
    {
        number: "12",
        question: "Reginald Kenneth Dwight is better known by what name?",
        answer: "elton john",
        hint: "Middle name Hercules"
    },
    {
        number: "13",
        question: "What was the name of Amy Winehouse’s second and final studio album released in 2006 and reached number one in multiple countries across the globe?",
        answer: "back to black",
        hint: "Released: 2006"
    },
    {
        number: "14",
        question: "Which band had a huge international hit album in 2002 with the record “A Rush of Blood to the Head”?",
        answer: "coldplay",
        hint: "Lead singer Chris Martin"
    },
    {
        number: "15",
        question: "Knights in White Satin was a 1967 hit for which band?",
        answer: "the moody blues",
        hint: "From Birmingham"
    },
    {
        number: "16",
        question: "Which band sang The Final Countdown?",
        answer: "europe",
        hint: "This band is from Sweden"
    },
    {
        number: "17",
        question: "What was David Bowie’s real surname?",
        answer: "jones",
        hint: "His original name was David Robert J****"
    },
    {
        number: "18",
        question: "How many members are there in South Korean mega boyband BTS?",
        answer: "7",
        hint: "Between 5 and 9"
    },
    {
        number: "19",
        question: "Which talent show judge managed Westlife?",
        answer: "louis walsh",
        hint: "Born Kiltimagh, Ireland"
    },
    {
        number: "20",
        question: "Who sang the 1965 James Bond theme, Thunderball?",
        answer: "Tom Jones",
        hint: "Born Treforest, Pontypridd"
    }

]

// british
const quiz7 = [
    {
        number: "1",
        question: "What is the highest mountain in Great Britain?",
        answer: "ben nevis",
        hint: "Located in Scotland"
    },
    {
        number: "2",
        question: "Which city has the nickname the ‘city of dreaming spires’?",
        answer: "oxford",
        hint: "Home to Magdalen College"
    },
    {
        number: "3",
        question: "Catatonia are a famous band from Wales, but who is their lead singer?",
        answer: "cerys matthews",
        hint: "Born 11 April 1969"
    },
    {
        number: "4",
        question: "Which of the following cities is the furthest north: Leeds, Liverpool or Manchester?",
        answer: "leeds",
        hint: "Home to the Royal Armouries houses"
    },
    {
        number: "5",
        question: "The Suffolk Punch is a breed of which animal?",
        answer: "horse",
        hint: "These animals were domesticated on the plains of northern Kazakstan over 5000 years ago"
    },
    {
        number: "6",
        question: "What is the most common street name in Great Britain? ",
        answer: "high street",
        hint: "Typically where most shops are located in towns and villages"
    },
    {
        number: "7",
        question: "Which village in Wales shares its name with a term meaning to ‘say something indistinctly and quietly’?",
        answer: "mumbles",
        hint: "Located in the county of Swansea"
    },
    {
        number: "8",
        question: "Which is the only town in England with a name ending with an exclamation mark?",
        answer: "westward ho!",
        hint: "Located in Devon"
    },
    {
        number: "9",
        question: "Which 13th-century Scottish warrior did Mel Gibson play in the 1995 film Braveheart?",
        answer: "william wallace",
        hint: "Layed to rest in London"
    },
    {
        number: "10",
        question: "The River Severn is the longest river in Britain at 354 km, but which is the second longest?",
        answer: "river thames",
        hint: "Famous for running through London"
    },
    {
        number: "11",
        question: "Which famous jazz club has the address 47 Frith Street, London?",
        answer: "Ronnie Scott",
        hint: "Located in Soho"
    },
    {
        number: "12",
        question: "In which county would you find the White Cliffs of Dover?",
        answer: "kent",
        hint: "Couny located in the South-east of england"
    },
    {
        number: "13",
        question: "Who was the first monarch to use Buckingham Palace as their official residence?",
        answer: "queen victoria",
        hint: "These royal adopted the title Empress of India on 1st May 1876"
    },
    {
        number: "14",
        question: "8 Ball, Easy Peeler and Clockwork Tangerine are all types of British what?",
        answer: "craft beer",
        hint: "popular alcaholic drink"
    },
    {
        number: "15",
        question: "What is the national flower of Wales?",
        answer: "daffodil",
        hint: "Yellow and spring flowering."
    },
    {
        number: "16",
        question: "What is the capital city of Scotland?",
        answer: "edinburgh",
        hint: "Affectionatly nicknamed Auld Reekie"
    },
    {
        number: "17",
        question: "Which metal shares its name with a famous London theatre? ",
        answer: "palladium",
        hint: "These theatre is located in Soho London"
    },
    {
        number: "18",
        question: "Alnwick Castle was used as the exterior shots in which film series? ",
        answer: "harry potter",
        hint: "A popular childs book by JK Rowling"
    },
    {
        number: "19",
        question: "What was 32 inches in 1512, 35 inches by the 1520s, and then 54 inches in 1545?",
        answer: "King Henry VIII’s waist",
        hint: "This King is famous for this attribute"
    },
    {
        number: "20",
        question: "Which mountain range is often described as the ‘backbone of England’?",
        answer: "The Pennines",
        hint: "The highest point is Cross Fell"
    }

]

// animals
const quiz8 = [
    {
        number: "1",
        question: "What name is given to an adult female sheep?",
        answer: "ewe",
        hint: "Three letter palindrome"
    },
    {
        number: "2",
        question: "Which large marine mammals are sometimes referred to as 'sea cows'?",
        answer: "manatees",
        hint: "-----"
    },
    {
        number: "3",
        question: "Which country is the natural habitat and home of lemurs?",
        answer: "madagascar",
        hint: "Island of the coast of Africa"
    },
    {
        number: "4",
        question: "Name the slowest animal in the world.",
        answer: "sloth",
        hint: "One of the seven deadly sins"
    },
    {
        number: "5",
        question: "All six legs of an ant are attach to which body part?",
        answer: "thorax",
        hint: "This is the middle part of the ant"
    },
    {
        number: "6",
        question: "Which animal never sleeps?",
        answer: "bullfrog",
        hint: "Large amphibian native to North America"
    },
    {
        number: "7",
        question: "Which animal has the longest lifespan?",
        answer: "bowhead whale",
        hint: "Lives in the arctic and sub arctic waters"
    },
    {
        number: "8",
        question: "What type of animal is a Mexican Hairless?",
        answer: "dog",
        hint: "Commonly referred to as man's best friend"
    },
    {
        number: "9",
        question: "How many legs does a lobster have?",
        answer: "10",
        hint: "Between 6 and 12"
    },
    {
        number: "10",
        question: "What is a group of giraffes known as?",
        answer: "tower",
        hint: "A word for a tall man made object for looking out from"
    },
    {
        number: "11",
        question: "What gives the flamingo it's distinctive pink/orange colour?",
        answer: "algea",
        hint: "A certain type of ( ) they eat"
    },
    {
        number: "12",
        question: "What do butterflies use their proboscis for?",
        answer: "Eating",
        hint: "Collecting nectar is a form of ( ) for them"
    },
    {
        number: "13",
        question: "Which animal has a Spanish name which when translated into English means 'little armoured one'?",
        answer: "armadillo",
        hint: "Typically found in Central and south America"
    },
    {
        number: "14",
        question: "What part of the world is the Capybara native to?",
        answer: "south america",
        hint: "The word Capybara is from Spanish and Portuguese origins"
    },
    {
        number: "15",
        question: "What do squids, snails and oysters have in common?",
        answer: "they are molluscs",
        hint: "There are around 85,000 decendents of this animal"
    },
    {
        number: "16",
        question: "Which flightless bird is the emblem of New Zealand?",
        answer: "kiwi",
        hint: "This animal is a slang term for New Zealanders"
    },
    {
        number: "17",
        question: "Which creature has the largest brain in proportion to its body?",
        answer: "ant",
        hint: "Think small"
    },
    {
        number: "18",
        question: "Which bird can fly backwards?",
        answer: "hummingbird",
        hint: "Famous for its abillity to hover in place to collect nectar"
    },
    {
        number: "19",
        question: "What substance  are shark skeletons made of?",
        answer: "cartilage",
        hint: "Also found in the human nose and ears"
    },
    {
        number: "20",
        question: "Which is the only venomous snake native to the UK?",
        answer: "adder",
        hint: "Usually found in woodland and heathland"
    }

]

// film
const quiz9 = [
    {
        number: "1",
        question: "How many James Bond films have there been?",
        answer: "26",
        hint: "There have been 24 official films"
    },
    {
        number: "2",
        question: "When was Monty Python's Life of Brian released?",
        answer: "1979",
        hint: "This is the year John Wayne died"
    },
    {
        number: "3",
        question: "In which two British cities is Trainspotting set?",
        answer: "edinburgh and london",
        hint: "The first is known as Auld Reekie and the second is capitol of England "
    },
    {
        number: "4",
        question: "Who directed the film Trainspotting?",
        answer: "danny boyle",
        hint: "More recent works include Slumdog millionaire and 127 hours"
    },
    {
        number: "5",
        question: "Who played King George VI in The King's Speech?",
        answer: "colin firth",
        hint: "Born in GrayShott 10th September 1960"
    },
    {
        number: "6",
        question: "How many Bridget Jones films are there?",
        answer: "3",
        hint: "Between 2 and 5"
    },
    {
        number: "7",
        question: "And who plays the iconic Bridget?",
        answer: "renee zellweger",
        hint: "Born in Texas 25th April 1969"
    },
    {
        number: "8",
        question: "Name the actor who played Harry Potter?",
        answer: "danial radcliffe",
        hint: "Born London 23rd July 1989"
    },
    {
        number: "9",
        question: "Name the actor who played Professor McGonagall?",
        answer: "maggie smith",
        hint: "More recent works include Downton Abbey"
    },
    {
        number: "10",
        question: "Stanley Kubrick's 1971 version of 'A Clockwork Orange' is a British cult classic. But who wrote the novel?",
        answer: "anthony burgess",
        hint: "Born Manchester 25th February 1917"
    },
    {
        number: "11",
        question: "Which airport is the opening scene of Love Actually set in?",
        answer: "Heathrow",
        hint: "An airport located in London"
    },
    {
        number: "12",
        question: "Name the actor who played Django in the film Django unchained?",
        answer: "jamie foxx",
        hint: "Real name Eric Marlon Bishop"
    },
    {
        number: "13",
        question: "Withnail and I is a 1987 British comedy written and directed by Bruce Robinson. But where in London do Withnail and I live?",
        answer: "camden town",
        hint: "Famed for its market and fashion warren"
    },
    {
        number: "14",
        question: "Julia Roberts stars in the iconic rom-com Notting Hill. But what are the occupations of the character she plays?",
        answer: "actress",
        hint: "The same job she has outside of the film"
    },
    {
        number: "15",
        question: "What type of dance is the 2000 film Billy Elliot about?",
        answer: "ballet",
        hint: "The type of dance originated during the Italian Renaissance"
    },
    {
        number: "16",
        question: "Who played Carrie in Four Weddings and a Funeral?",
        answer: "andy macdowell",
        hint: "Born South Carolina 21st April 1958"
    },
    {
        number: "17",
        question: "The famous adaptation of Price & Prejudice starring Keira Knightly was released in what year?",
        answer: "2005",
        hint: "Between 2003 and 2007"
    },
    {
        number: "18",
        question: "This is England (2006) was directed by who?",
        answer: "shane meadows",
        hint: "Also known for directing Dead Man's Shoes"
    },
    {
        number: "19",
        question: "Who played The Queen in the 2006 film about Her Royal Majesty?",
        answer: "helen mirren",
        hint: "Born London 26th July 1945"
    },
    {
        number: "20",
        question: "Who directed the 2009 adaptation of Sherlock Holmes?",
        answer: "Two and a half",
        hint: "Also known for hit movies like Snatch and Lock, Stock and Two Smoking Barrels"
    }

]